ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/095
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 23-25 Records
1972-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 23-25
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/095
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records (documents), photographs.
The collection contains files of International Ladies Garment Workers Union Local 23-25, Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers. Included are files of the Coalition of Labor Union Women, as well as press releases, news clippings, and other printed material.
5493127
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, April 13, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Locals 23 and 25 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), as well as the local resulting from their merger, local 23-25, also known as the Blouse, Skirt, and Sportswear Workers' Union, were based in New York, New York. Local 23 was chartered in 1903; Local 25 was chartered in 1905. Locals 23 and 25 merged and changed their name to 23-25 officially on November 27, 1963.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains files of International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 23-25, Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers, documenting the work and members of the local. Included are files of the Coalition of Labor Union Women, as well as press releases, news clippings, and other printed material.
Subjects with sufficient material include information packets and meetings regarding the 1990 U.S. Census, in which the local and May Chen were involved with the Chinatown Census Committee to get the individuals and union members of Chinatown counted. Additionally, Chinatown is documented through industry studies and proposals. There is a digest of articles from the "Chinatown Press and at the end of the collection a large amount of collected newspaper articles and clippings, mostly from Chinese publications. And finally, there is substantial material on the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW). Most of this involves the Asian members of Local 23-25 who formed the Chinese Committee (see also 5780/059).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/059: ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/059 P: ILGWU Local 23-25 Photographs 5780/059 PUBS: ILGWU Local 23-25 Publications 5780/095 G: ILGWU Local 23-25 graphics
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Women's clothing industry--New York (State)--New York.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Industrial relations--United States.; Industrial relations--New York (State)--New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 23-25 (New York, N.Y.)
5493127
- 1990 Census Campaign Materials [folder 1 of 2], 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  English and Chinese
- 1990 Census Campaign Materials [folder 2 of 2], 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1990 Census Campaign. Chinatown Committee Materials (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1990 Census Campaign. Chinatown Committee Poster and Essay Contests, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Local 23-25 Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers Union. 1986 Statue of Liberty Essay Winners [folder 1 of 2], 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Local 23-25 Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers Union. 1986 Statue of Liberty Essay Winners [folder 2 of 2], 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- New York Statue of Liberty Centennial Commission. "Dreams and Visions from a New Generation of Americans", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Local 23-25 Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers Union. Study of the Garment Industry in Chinatown, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Chinatown Redevelopment Proposal, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bathgate Industrial Park and Eastside Redevelopment Reports, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Buckhurst Fish Hutton Katz Chinatown Proposal, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Capital Needs and Priorities for the City of New York. Statement of the NYC Planning Commission, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Crown Heights Area Maintenance Program, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "From Chinatown Press" [folder 1 of 2], 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "From the Chinatown Press" [folder 2 of 2], 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Local 23-25. The Chinatown Garment Industry Study. An Overview, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Union News, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Founding Celebration Materials, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. New York City Chapter, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Pamphlets and Logo Designs (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Coalition of Labor Union Woman. Chinese Committee Materials, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Coalition of Union Labor Women. Work and Family Materials (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Civil Rights Materials, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. South Africa Publications, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. New York City Chapter Executive Board Meeting Agendas, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. International Women's Day Celebration, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Fourth Biennial Convention, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. National Executive Board Meeting Memoranda and Materials, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Coalition of Union Labor Women. Immigration Workshop, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Chinese Committee Activity Reports, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Fifth Biennial Celebration Materials, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Miscellaneous Event Promotion, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. American Family Celebration Materials and Local Action Kit, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. American Family Celebration Travel Guides and Itineraries, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. International Women's Day Organizational Information, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Informational Pamphlets and Notices, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. Informational Pamphlets and Notices, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women. New York City Chapter Executive Board Materials, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Local 23-25. The Chinatown Garment Industry Study, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings and Photocopies [folder 1 of 5], 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings and Photocopies [folder 2 of 5], 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings and Photocopies [folder 3 of 5], 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings and Photocopies [folder 4 of 5], 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings and Photocopies [folder 5 of 5], 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Local 23-25, ILGWU. Campaign Materials, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Fee, Ben. Local 23-25, ILGWU. Newsletter Templates and Drafts (Box 3, Folder 7)
- United in 1994 Campaign. Meeting Attendance Cards (Box 3, Folder 8)
  May 5, 1994